Nicole Miles

Muncie, IN 47304 ndmiles@hotmail.com +1 765 744 1052

Compassionate and skilled RN Case Manager with over 10 years of leadership & management experience. Excellent communication skills with knowledge of Medicare health regulations and JCAHO standards. Passionate about providing quality, culturally congruent care for a wide variety of patients with diverse needs. A dedicated advocate for health equity that provides improved access to care and encourages preventative and patient-centered care.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

RN Case Manager

Indiana University Health - Muncie, IN February 2021 to Present

- Responsible for the assessment, planning, implementation, coordination, monitoring, and evaluation of services across the continuum of care to ensure quality patient outcomes and appropriate utilization of health care services.
- Coordinated home care, home infusion, and durable medical equipment to reduce stress for patients and wait time.
- Obtained recommendations for inpatient or outpatient level of care by discussing cases with the interdisciplinary medical team.
- Updated and maintained discharge plan of care with the physician, members of the health care team, patients, and families ensured accuracy of the patient treatment plan.

Certified Mobile Research Nurse (CMRN) PRN

PCM TRIALS

December 2020 to Present

Trained and certified to follow GCP and complete trial-specific training to provide mobile visits for subjects enrolled in clinical trials. Provide source documentation for each visit and a variety of clinical services including assessments, injections, infusions and blood draws.

Program Manager of Case Management

Seeds of Life, LLC - Anderson, IN July 2018 to March 2021

- Manage day to day activities of 13 Case Managers, Homemaker aides, and visitation facilitators as assigned. Functions as a Case Manager when work caseloads required.
- Collect information regarding current/past behavioral/mental health, family history of mental health, medical health, education, and the effects of symptoms on daily life activities. (Utilizes CANS/ANSA, Biopsychosocial, CAGE, and additional intake Assessments)
- Develop initial and ongoing treatment goals and objectives to assist the consumer in meeting their stated goals

- Maintain practices and protocols, provides orientation and on-the-job training to assure staff are well prepared for their roles, and monitor work performance.
- Facilitate bi-monthly staff meetings and monthly 1-on-1 meetings with assigned team members.

Registered Nurse Cancer Care

St Vincent Ascension Health - Anderson, IN July 2020 to January 2021

- Implements and monitors patient care plans. Monitors, records and communicates patient condition as appropriate.
- Serves as a primary coordinator of all disciplines for well-coordinated patient care.
- Notes and carries out physician and nursing orders.
- Assesses and coordinates patient's discharge planning needs with members of the healthcare team.

RN Case Manager

ViaQuest Hospice - Muncie, IN August 2020 to December 2020

- Through the use of clinical tools and information/data review, conducts an evaluation of member's needs and benefit plan eligibility and facilitates integrative functions as well as smooth transition to medicare/private insurance programs and plans. Applies clinical judgment to the incorporation of strategies designed to reduce risk factors and barriers and address complex health and social indicators which impact care planning and resolution of member issues
- Utilize the nursing process to assess, plan, intervene, and evaluate patient care
- Visit patients and families in their place of residence or in the hospital to assess for appropriateness, explain services, monitor condition, or admit to hospice services in accordance with the admission procedure (OASIS, FAST, PHQ9, Zung, PPS, KPS assessments)
- Consult and coordinate with healthcare team members and the interdisciplinary team regarding interventions and patient care.
- Provide education and support related to symptom management and the physical aspects of End of Life care for the patient/family/caregiver and/or facility team as appropriate.
- Communicate patient/family/caregiver immediate needs and significant IDG Care Plan issues to the patient's assigned RN Case Manager

Recovery Care Specialist

Odyssey Behavioral Healthcare - Anderson, IN August 2017 to February 2019

- * Responsible for supporting recovery and monitoring the health, safety and wellbeing of women in treatment to overcome eating disorders.
- * Provide therapeutic opportunities for clients to process their feelings.
- * Monitor client mealtimes and snacks and provide support and compassion for clients struggling to eat.

Supervisor of Home and Community Based Services

Aspire Indiana - Anderson, IN August 2018 to January 2019

- Facilitated, coordinated, and evaluated the operation and efficiency of home based services, and provide supervision to assigned staff (10), maintain good communication with school personnel, monitor caseload assignments and ensure the quality of documentation.
- Worked with adults who are in addiction services and clients with a serious mental illness. Duties included: teaching recovery-based skills to clients with addictions, orienting consumers/clients to the

psychiatric rehabilitation process, assessing critical skills functioning related to the consumers/clients identified goals, assessing the needs and strengths of consumers/clients, teaching critical skills (e.g., hygiene, personal care, safety, meal preparation, housekeeping, money management, etc.), as needed to reach the individual's goal, teaching from lesson plans/curriculums, organizing and supervising community-based activities for consumers/clients, coordinating with consumers/clients to develop a person-centered treatment plan for services, managing crisis situations, conducting home visits, referring/linking consumers/clients to needed services or community opportunities.

• Worked to advance and support Aspire's mission, vision, values, and strategic priorities by coordinating services within the Aspire continuum to ensure the highest quality of client care.

Patient Care Assistant (PCA)

Indiana University Health - Muncie, IN October 2017 to September 2018

- As a bedside caregiver, provided a great patient experience by anticipating the needs of patients such as providing drinks, assisting with meal ordering, encouraging walking, assisting with baths, and providing clean linens and gowns.
- Provided Point of care testing, monitored patient input and output, administered blood draws and prepared patients for surgical procedures.
- Performed EMR charting.

State Health Coordinator (Health Services Management)

Transition Resources Corporation - Pendleton, IN October 2014 to April 2017

- Supervised a team of Health Specialists and nutrition staff (10 staff) including evaluating performance, setting schedules and mediating conflicts and procuring health and nutritional products for the program.
- Coordinated case management services to ensure each child and pregnant woman received access to proper healthcare
- Complete regular compliance audits of child medical records and facilities to ensure programs withheld State, Federal regulation and licensing standards.
- Monitored staff training and credential renewal schedules.
- Responsible for building and maintaining strong client and community relationships
- Track all reporting requirements and prepare monthly, quarterly, and annual reports as required by the Office of Head Start.
- Tracked departmental spending and monitored staff overtime to decrease overspending.
- Coordinated delivery of cost effective health care services including securing (and annually renewing medical and dental agreements) providers for the provisions of EPSDT physicals and dental exams for enrolled TRC children and pregnant women.
- Facilitated health literacy education and First Aid/CPR to staff, parents and family members.

Clinical Secretary- Neonatal ICU

I.U. Health Ball Memorial Hospital - Muncie, IN January 2013 to December 2016

- * Responsible for the flow of communication and all clerical activities in Pediatric, Labor and Delivery, Mother Baby and Neonatal Intensive Care Units.
- * Served as a liaison for the daily communication and operation of the department between staff, patients and all customers.

* Coordinated and maintained many facets of data collection utilizing various equipment for the department.

Director of Agencies and Programs

Second Harvest Food Bank of East Central Indiana -SHFB (Non-Profit sector) - Muncie, IN May 2011 to October 2014

- Participated as a key member of SHFB's leadership team, with responsibility for input on all major decisions for SHFB's future.
- Managed a \$2M budget, and provided monthly explanations for differences in total expenses and surplus/deficits greater than the designated amount to the Board of Directors.
- Managed the development, implementation, analysis, improvement, and expansion of SHFB's food programs with the goal of creating effective partnerships and approaches to ending hunger in East Central Indiana.
- Inspired and supervised the Food Programs staff and interns, including hiring, training, providing professional development opportunities, and performance reviews. Oversaw program staff responsible for the emergency food assistance program (TEFAP) Tailgate, Commodity Supplemental Food Program (CSFP), and Child Nutrition Programs.
- Ensured that SHFB met all programmatic requirements and regulations of Feeding America, the State of Indiana, and stakeholders.
- Managed grants and funding streams for programs, and ensure administrative sustainability for all programs in the department.

Team Lead-Call Center Operations (Supervisor)

International Business Machines-IBM November 2007 to January 2011

- Lead group of technical support advisors (20) by example, established high performance culture and personal dedication
- Evaluates team and department level data and trends to drive improvements. Provides suggestions that impact business processes and balances needs of all stakeholders
- Influence all aspects of performance management including staffing decisions (including hiring and terminations as appropriate), goal setting, development planning, performance evaluations, performance improvement, motivation and recognition.

Unit Collections Manager - Call Center Operations

Sallie Mae

November 2005 to November 2007

- Actively spoke with borrowers, monitored calls and provided on-the-job development of 15 direct reports.
- Coordinated with floor manager on review of monthly performance reports to develop strategies for identifying areas of under producing segments of the portfolio and how to focus recovery efforts among the staff.
- Trained/coached existing staff members in areas of collections and skip-tracing and be available to answer questions from the staff on an ongoing basis.
- Frequently met with Sr. Collections Manager (SCM)/Operations Manager to review statistics to identify any necessary plan of correction
- Assisted the SCM with call audits and inform the staff of results and requirements for improvement.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Nursing

Western Governors University - Salt Lake City, UT March 2021 to Present

Associate in Nursing

Ivy Tech Community College - New Castle, IN January 2019 to May 2020

Bachelor's Degree in Sociology

Ball State University - Muncie, IN December 2010

Nursing Licenses

RN

Expires: October 2023

State: IN

Skills

- Customer Service (10+ years)
- Community Outreach (6 years)
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- Management (10+ years)
- Interviewing (10+ years)
- Hiring (10+ years)
- Recruiting (3 years)
- Coaching (10+ years)
- EMR Systems (8 years)
- Experience with Children (10+ years)
- Microsoft Excel
- · Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Outlook
- Call Center (5 years)
- Case Management (5 years)
- Program Management
- Meeting Facilitation
- Employee Evaluation
- Patient Care (4 years)
- Word Processing

- Motivational Interviewing
- Social Work
- Medical terminology
- Hospital Experience
- Performance Management
- Nursing
- Medication Administration
- Employee Orientation
- Hospice care
- Public speaking
- Supervising experience
- Home care
- Clinical trials
- · Clinical research
- Intake Experience
- English
- Triage
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Crisis Intervention
- Data Collection
- Time management
- Leadership
- Discharge planning
- Senior care
- Mac OS
- · Google Suite
- Windows
- · Acute care
- Supervisor (10+ years)
- · Care plans
- Documentation review
- · Patient monitoring

Languages

• English - Fluent

Certifications and Licenses

BLS for Healthcare Providers (CPR and AED)

Registered Nurse (RN)

July 2020 to October 2023

Compact Registered Nursing License

October 2021 to October 2023

BLS Certification

Assessments

Case Management & Social Work — Proficient

May 2020

Prioritizing case tasks, gathering information, and providing services without judgment.

Full results: Proficient

Management & Leadership Skills: Planning & Execution — Expert

June 2020

Planning and managing resources to accomplish organizational goals

Full results: Expert

Clinical Judgment — Highly Proficient

May 2020

Assessing a patient's condition and implementing the appropriate medical intervention.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Electronic Health Records: Best Practices — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Knowledge of EHR data, associated privacy regulations, and best practices for EHR use

Full results: Highly Proficient

General Manager (Hospitality) — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Solving group scheduling problems and reading and interpreting P&L statements

Full results: Highly Proficient

Case management & social work — Proficient

January 2021

Prioritizing case tasks, gathering information, and providing services without judgment

Full results: Proficient

Patient-focused care — Highly Proficient

November 2020

Addressing concerns and using sensitivity when responding to needs and feelings of patients

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Additional Information

References available upon request